tourisme-montreal.org 2018-01-23

# Privacy policy | Tourisme Montréal

Tourisme Montréal updated its Confidentiality and Privacy Policy on May 15, 2017. The main changes were:

  * Section 1 was converted into a table to better present how your personal information is used.
  * Clarifications were made concerning the use of cookies and how to deactivate them.
  * A procedure was added for removing your name from our mailing lists.

For access-to-information purposes, we have made the 2008 Tourisme Montréal Confidentiality and Privacy Policy available [here](https://s3.amazonaws.com/tmvideoprod/img/privacy-policy-2008.html).

This text details the Confidentiality and Privacy Policy developed by Tourisme Montréal (the “Policy”).

For more information on the terms of use of this Web site, please review our Terms of service

1\. Information collected about you

On all Tourisme Montréal Web pages where identifiable personal information is collected, Tourisme Montréal specifically lists all of the information required to access any product or service you request.

Identifiable personal information is that which refers to and serves to identify an individual. Unless required by law or a court order issued by a competent tribunal, Tourisme Montréal preserves the confidentiality of all personal information obtained about users of its Web sites. Tourisme Montréal does not sell or lease your identifiable personal information to anyone.

Personal information is collected by Tourisme Montréal on a fully transparent, voluntary basis. Information may be collected in several different situations, all of which are listed in the table below. In each of these scenarios, users who enter personal information authorize Tourisme Montréal to collect this information. All compulsory information that is collected has been deemed necessary and reasonable in light of the services provided by Tourisme Montréal.

* In surveys, when you authorize Tourisme Montréal to send you emails, your personal information (first and last names, email address, mailing address) is treated in the same way as when you sign up for a newsletter. 

2\. Sharing personal information

To provide the services you request and process your requests, Tourisme Montréal shares your personal information with authorized suppliers or service providers that are called upon to provide some services or perform certain tasks on behalf of Tourisme Montréal.  Although Tourisme Montréal publishes offers from travel suppliers or service providers that are reputable companies, it has not imposed any restrictions on these suppliers or service providers regarding the use or disclosure of your information without your consent. Therefore, we encourage you to review the privacy and confidentiality practices of any supplier or service provider whose products you book via Tourisme Montréal. In addition, these suppliers or service providers may also contact you as necessary to obtain additional information.

Tourisme Montréal does not disclose any personal information relative to a user unless it is used exclusively to answer a specific user request or is intended for explicitly authorized purposes. Furthermore, the confidentiality of electronically transmitted information is ensured by use of stringent security measures.

WHEN YOU SUPPLY IDENTIFIABLE PERSONAL INFORMATION TO TOURISME MONTRÉAL WHILE USING THE SERVICES OFFERED ON THIS WEB SITE, YOU CONSENT TO (I) THE COLLECTION OF THIS INFORMATION BY TOURISME MONTRÉAL, (II) THE DISCLOSURE OF THIS INFORMATION TO SUPPLIERS, SERVICE PROVIDERS AND BUSINESS PARTNERS OF TOURISME MONTRÉAL FOR THE ABOVEMENTIONED PURPOSES, AND (III) THE PRESERVATION OF THIS INFORMATION BY TOURISME MONTRÉAL FOR FUTURE USE RELATED TO ULTERIOR REQUESTS.

Please note that Tourisme Montréal reserves the right to disclose your personal information to a third party without your prior consent in the following events:

  * If your conduct on this Web site breaches the Terms of service;
  * Should Tourisme Montréal deem in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to identify, contact in view of or undertake legal actions against a person that could hinder or cause prejudice (intentionally or not) to the rights or properties of Tourisme Montréal or those of other users;
  * In the event that Tourisme Montréal is forced to comply with a warrant or order from a tribunal with respect to an offence committed or on the verge of being committed; or
  * In the event that Tourisme Montréal deems in good faith that the law requires such disclosure, including sharing personal information with other companies and organizations for the purpose of preventing fraud, the whole in order to comply with any legal or regulatory requirements.

3\. Security measures

We want our members and visitors to feel confident about using the Tourisme Montréal Web sites to plan and book travel services. As a result, we are committed to protecting the information we collect. Tourisme Montréal has implemented a security program to protect the information stored in its systems from unauthorized access. Currently, Tourisme Montréal can only store the information you provide when you register to become a Tourisme Montréal member or create a user profile.

Our systems are configured to encrypt and scramble data, and are protected by industry-standard technologies and firewalls. When you transmit personal information to Tourisme Montréal over the Internet, your data is protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption to ensure safe transmission.

Notwithstanding the security measures deployed by Tourisme Montréal to ensure that third parties are unable to obtain your personal information via its Web site, complete confidentiality and security on the Internet cannot be guaranteed by anyone at this time. Communications via the Internet are subject to interception, loss or alteration. YOU ACKNOWLEDGE THAT NEITHER TOURISME MONTRÉAL NOR ITS GROUP MEMBERS CAN BE HELD LIABLE FOR DAMAGES RESULTING FROM THE TRANSMISSION OF CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION OR PERSONAL INFORMATION OVER THE INTERNET, AND THAT SUCH COMMUNICATIONS ARE AT YOUR OWN RISK.

The means of protecting your personal information used by Tourisme Montréal also apply to the internal use of your information.

All of your personal information is kept on our secure servers located in Canada and the United States, and only authorized personnel from Tourisme Montréal and its suppliers have access to it. In addition, the servers used to store your personal information are kept on a secure site.

The means of protecting your personal information also extend to our Web services suppliers. When personal information is handled, data governance shall include procedures for handling and converting data to ensure that users’ personal information is protected. These operations shall be specific to each environment.

Tourisme Montréal only keeps your personal information as long as necessary for a specific purpose or as required by law. Tourisme Montréal has implemented deletion measures for personal information that is obsolete or no longer necessary.

These measures are specified in the table appearing in Section 1 of this document.

4\. Use of cookies

Some Tourisme Montréal sites store cookies, permanent or otherwise, on the user’s hard drive. These cookies help facilitate browsing by entering the user’s language preference. Other permanent cookies make it possible, among other things, to know how often a user navigates one of the sites during a predetermined time period.

Finally, some cookies are used to collect general, non-identifying information. Mainly, these cookies help determine what types of advertisements match the user. The cookie is associated with a unique number identifying the computer (IP address). The IP address shall be used to recommend content to you according to your geolocation only. It cannot be combined with other information collected about you. The cookie **does not** contain the user’s name, address, telephone number, email address or other identifying information. Our cookie only collects general, non-identifying information such as the computer operating system, browser, visited webpages and time of use, the Internet provider’s geographic location and anonymous demographic information, such as gender or age category, collected via anonymous online surveys. Cookies are also sent from the servers of our authorized suppliers and service providers. We use their services to determine and analyze how you use our Web platforms so that we can improve their quality. Only general, non-identifying information is collected for this purpose. In addition, our authorized suppliers and service providers comply with recognized principles for protecting personal information and must also respect their own privacy policies.

Tourisme Montréal uses social media to enhance its Web presence. Users who choose to communicate with Tourisme Montréal via social media must read the terms of service and privacy policies of these third-party service providers and the applications used to access them.

Cookies must be enabled in your browser in order for some of Tourisme Montréal’s sites to work properly. However, users may then delete cookies from their computer or mobile device without it affecting how Tourisme Montréal sites work on their computer. Alternatively, users can also deactivate advertiser cookies.

**Deactivating advertiser cookies**

Tourisme Montréal allows users to deactivate the cookie associated with advertisements, which prevents the use of specific information about the user’s browsing history or behaviour for targeted advertising purposes. Deactivating this cookie does not prevent ads from being sent to a computer, but it does prevent data from being associated with the computer browser and thereby prevents targeted advertising.

Please note that the cookie deactivation mechanism used by Tourisme Montréal requires that your browser accept third-party cookies from Tourisme Montréal.

If you wish to deactivate behavioural targeting from Tourisme Montréal, please [click here](http://mis.mtl.org/optout.html?url=http%3A//www.mtl.org/). To reactivate behavioural targeting so that you can receive ads that match your browsing history, please delete the cookies from your browser.

Please note that all other cookies associated with your browser will not be affected. Tourisme Montréal ads will be deactivated for the duration of your browser’s lifetime on your hard drive or until you delete the cookie from your hard drive. The cookie deactivation process will delete the cookie file but not the cookie itself. You must keep the deactivation cookie in your computer in order to be identified as a user who has deactivated the cookie. If you change your mind after deactivating the cookie, click on the aforementioned clickable link to edit your choice.

5\. Links to other sites

There are several sections throughout Tourisme Montréal Web sites that may link you to other Web sites that are not operated under this Policy. When you click on such links to access these sites, the current Policy no longer applies. We therefore recommend that you review the privacy statements and confidentiality practices of all third-party Web sites to understand their practices in terms of collecting, using and disclosing your information. These links are provided for user convenience only. Tourisme Montréal in no way controls, endorses or guarantees the sites linked to this portal and cannot be held liable for their content or practices, particularly with respect to privacy and confidentiality.

6\. Access to your personal information

Tourisme Montréal believes that its site members and visitors should have control over how their personal information is collected and used. You can access the information about you in your user profile on the concerned Tourisme Montréal Web platform. 

Users may ask to review, correct or delete personal information Tourisme Montréal keeps in their files. For any request, comment or complaint in this regard, please contact [info@mtl.org](mailto:privacy@tourisme-montreal.org) and supply contact information that will allow us to identify you. You may also write to us at the following address:

Tourisme Montréal  
Privacy Policy  
800 René-Lévesque Boulevard West, suite 2450  
Montréal, Québec  
H3B 1X9 Canada

7\. Laws governing the protection of personal information

Tourisme Montréal’s Web sites are published in Québec, Canada. This Policy was therefore drafted in accordance with applicable Canadian laws, among others, the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act and the Province of Québec’s Act respecting the protection of personal information in the private sector.

8\. Changes to this Policy

This Policy was drafted by Tourisme Montréal and published on the Tourisme Montréal Web site on May 7, 2008. Tourisme Montréal reserves the right to make any modifications to this Policy as a result of changes in the technological or legal landscape, or simply as a result of any modification to its Web sites, at any time, at its sole discretion and without prior notice or notification. If material changes are made to this Policy or to the manner in which Tourisme Montréal will use your identifiable personal information, Tourisme Montréal will prominently post such changes prior to their application.

CONTINUING TO ACCESS THIS WEB SITE PURSUANT TO ANY UPDATE OF THIS POLICY REPRESENTS YOUR CONSENT TO THE USE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION ACCORDING TO THE MODIFIED POLICY.

9\. Amending e-mailing lists

If you wish to be added to (or removed from) one or several of our e-mailing lists, or if you wish to change the way we communicate with you, please contact us as stipulated in Article 6.

You may also, without our assistance, subscribe to our electronic messages by: (i) checking the Subscribe to newsletter box when creating your profile; or (ii) filling out the form available at the footer of our website.  

If you would like to unsubscribe from these lists, simply: (i) click the Unsubscribe link in the email sent to you from Tourisme Montréal; or (ii) edit your preferences in your user profile on the Tourisme Montréal website.
